Jacques Van Der Merwe

Mobile: +380 73 009 3146 Linkedin: linkedin.com/in/jacques-vandermerwe

Email: jacquesvandermerwe1974@gmail.com Github: github.com/jacquesme

Professional Summary

A dedicated and goal driven individual with a positive and professional attitude. Enjoys being part of a team effort to grow and establish new profitable business and solutions. Quick adaptive and open minded to new concepts, strategies and freely share experiences and knowledge with team members. Passionate about learning different technologies and applying newly acquired skills in new exciting projects. Having experience in contract negotiations, team management, client services and P&L responsibilities made me a valuable asset for my previous company and this experience can add value to future employers.

Self-confident, effective communicator that can easily display true empathy but be assertive as well. Achieving success in challenging situations by applying honesty and maintaining a positive attitude with inquisitiveness and some creativity. Value loyalty and honesty in team working relationships.

Reason for career change:

Grateful for the wonderful career that I had, I decided to take a leap of faith to follow my passions. Although I had many successes in my previous career, I am not a natural sale's person or negotiator. I am creative and artistic with a love of technologies. Being a visual person with a passion for coding drives my inquisitiveness for all things Front-end development related.

Skills & Achievements

Experience:

Languages:	Libraries & FrameWorks:	Other:	
✓ HTML5	✓ Bootstrap	✓ GitHub	✓ Nodemon
✓ CSS3	✓ jQuery	✓ GitBash	

Working Knowledge:

Languages:	Libraries & FrameWorks:	Other:	
✓ JavaScript es5/es6	✓ React.js	✓ Node.js	✓ Webpack
✓ SQL		√ Npm	

Career History

2018 - present Openclassrooms (Front-end Development)

- · Integrate a WorPress theme for a client.
- · Map out a technical solution for a food delivery website using UML & phpMyAdmin.
- · Created a quote generator in JavaScript.
- · Created a turn-based board game in JavaScript & jQuery.
- · Created a restaurant review site with google Api.
- Enhanced an existing website, test with Jasmine, analyse site performance and create technical documentation.

2014 - 2017 Kal Tire Mining Tyre Operations Manager

- · Coordinates sales effort by managing logistics and service groups.
- Develops clear and effective written proposals/quotations for existing/ prospective customers.
- Expedites the resolution of customer problems and complaints.
- Establishes, develops and maintains a professional business relationship with existing/ prospective customers to generate new business which increase sales revenue.
- · Manage and coordinates administration and inventory department.

2011 - 2013 Kal Tire Mining Tyre Services Service Manager

2009 - 2011 Trentyre Services Service Manager

- Achieving maximum sales profitability, growth and account penetration within the Mining segment by effectively selling the company's products and services.
- Establishes, develops and maintains professional business relationships.
- Demonstrates products and services to existing/potential customers and assists them in selecting those best suited to their needs.
- Promotes/sells/secures orders from existing and prospective customers.

1998 - 2008 Trentyre Pty (Ltd) Sales Representative

- Achieving maximum sales profitability, growth and account penetration within the Mining segment by effectively selling the company's products and services.
- Establishes, develops and maintains professional business relationships.
- Demonstrates products and services to existing/potential customers and assists them in selecting those best suited to their needs.
- Promotes/sells/secures orders from existing and prospective customers.

Qualifications

- · 2018–2019 OpenClassrooms (Front End Web Development / Bachelor's-level Diploma EQF6)
- · 2013-2015 Harvard Business / KalTire (Operations Management / Company Diploma)
- · 2005–2007 Academy of Advanced Technologies (Project Design / Diploma)